<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-boston-subway</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024441/1897-03-04/ed-1/?sp=5&q=Boston+Dead+dead+explosion+flame+gas+Gas+Subway&st=text&r=0.239,0.386,0.463,0.493,0</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>/</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1897-09-19/ed-1/?sp=32&q=BOSTON+Boston+BOSTONS+SUBWAY+subway</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>UNDERGROUND TRAVEL.
T1IK BOSTON SUBWAY PARTLY COM?
PLETED AND IN OPERATION.
A BRI0I1TI.T UOIITED Tl NNW. AFKfU'.PlN?: RAPID
TRANSIT FOR BLECTRIO CARS CONORS
TIO? OV TUB BTREET9 RELIEVBD,
The subway for streetcars In Boston, a pari
of whli h has Ju il b >a op? n? -i for at rvlce. is an
em.???? of more than local Interest The ne
eesslty for some relief t? the i rowded thorough?
fares above it can besl be appre? lat? d, of course,
by H lonlans; but tl?.- Modem Aib.n.s is i?; no
means th.ily cltj In this countr) which is
beset with problems of the same character.
ThofO who :ii" familiar v.iih "!h<- lay of tiie
land" in Bosl? n remember thai Tremont-st. runs
In a ajenerall) north-and-aonth direction and
forms ihe istern boundary of th.- Common.
Ii i-; intersected by Rovlston-st., which consti?
tutes Ihe southern boundary of thai historic
parle On the Boylsl m and Tremonl st edges
of the Common there is a broad promenade.
known as the Mall. The main part of the sub?
ira. li. h Is w Id nough to a? commodate four
tracks, passes under ihe Tremonl st. Mall, and.
niter passing under Park-st, which lies along
the northern side if ine Common, extends mr
will extend, when completed) to Scollay ?Square,
thence eastward to Adams Square, ami finally
up northward again to Hayraarkel Square.
This terminus Is close to the great union rail?
way station .it the North End.
Ft en th.- oin, r of Tri mont and Boylston sts.
there are two extensions, wldn enough f>?r only
a double track. Boylston st. Mall for about '.k"> feet, and then
ascends an Incline through an op? n ul for ,'il*
feel The terminal station for this branch la
situated In th- Public Gardens. The other
branch reaches away to the southward, and. on
nearlng th<- Junction of Bhawmul ave. and Tn
mont-st., forks. A separate two-track incline
leads up into each of those streeta
Including th? Inclines, ihe subway has a total
length of about a mile and a half, und will con?
tain about five miles of track Al present the
branches from th.rn.-r of Boylston and Tre?
monl Bl.-. and th-- main line up to Park-Si. an
In operation. A great >l<-.il o? work has already
been done on the northern portion of the route,
arid it is h? i I thai everything all) be finished
within th> n \t eight months. Hi und wats
broken for the subway in April, 1805, twenty
Bine month- ago.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	      --- edit from here.
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id></id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id></id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
