<topics>
	<topic>
		<id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-boston-subway</id>
		<results>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024441/1897-03-04/ed-1/?sp=5&ampq=Boston+Dead+dead+explosion+flame+gas+Gas+Subway&ampst=text&ampr=0.239,0.386,0.463,0.493,0</id>
				<rel>0</rel>
				<text>/</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1897-09-19/ed-1/?sp=32&ampq=BOSTON+Boston+BOSTONS+SUBWAY+subway</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>UNDERGROUND TRAVEL.
T1IK BOSTON SUBWAY PARTLY COM?
PLETED AND IN OPERATION.
A BRI0I1TI.T UOIITED Tl NNW. AFKfU'.PlN?: RAPID
TRANSIT FOR BLECTRIO CARS CONORS
TIO? OV TUB BTREET9 RELIEVBD,
The subway for streetcars In Boston, a pari
of whli h has Ju il b >a op? n? -i for at rvlce. is an
em.???? of more than local Interest The ne
eesslty for some relief t? the i rowded thorough?
fares above it can besl be appre? lat? d, of course,
by H lonlans; but tl?.- Modem Aib.n.s is i?; no
means th.ily cltj In this countr) which is
beset with problems of the same character.
ThofO who :ii" familiar v.iih "!h<- lay of tiie
land" in Bosl? n remember thai Tremont-st. runs
In a ajenerall) north-and-aonth direction and
forms ihe istern boundary of th.- Common.
Ii i-; intersected by Rovlston-st., which consti?
tutes Ihe southern boundary of thai historic
parle On the Boylsl m and Tremonl st edges
of the Common there is a broad promenade.
known as the Mall. The main part of the sub?
ira. li. h Is w Id nough to a? commodate four
tracks, passes under ihe Tremonl st. Mall, and.
niter passing under Park-st, which lies along
the northern side if ine Common, extends mr
will extend, when completed) to Scollay ?Square,
thence eastward to Adams Square, ami finally
up northward again to Hayraarkel Square.
This terminus Is close to the great union rail?
way station .it the North End.
Ft en th.- oin, r of Tri mont and Boylston sts.
there are two extensions, wldn enough f>?r only
a double track. Boylston st. Mall for about '.k"> feet, and then
ascends an Incline through an op? n ul for ,'il*
feel The terminal station for this branch la
situated In th- Public Gardens. The other
branch reaches away to the southward, and. on
nearlng th<- Junction of Bhawmul ave. and Tn
mont-st., forks. A separate two-track incline
leads up into each of those streeta
Including th? Inclines, ihe subway has a total
length of about a mile and a half, und will con?
tain about five miles of track Al present the
branches from th.rn.-r of Boylston and Tre?
monl Bl.-. and th-- main line up to Park-Si. an
In operation. A great >l<-.il o? work has already
been done on the northern portion of the route,
arid it is h? i I thai everything all) be finished
within th> n \t eight months. Hi und wats
broken for the subway in April, 1805, twenty
Bine month- ago.
				</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn95079490/1897-10-23/ed-1/?sp=7&ampq=BOSTON+SUBWAY</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>
        THE BOSTON SUBWAY
SATISFACTORY SOLUTION OF THE
STREET CAR PROBLEM.
Contention of Trafllc In tli? Iluny Streets
of the Uub Relieved by Underground
Trolley Lines?Tunnels Tlmt Am Light,
Clean uud Attractive.
It is now possible to cross Tromont
street, Boston, at any point opposite tho
Common and at any time of day without
loss of life or limb. Tho new subway has
brought about tho change.
It 1 s an old tradition that tho fathers of
Boston, when thoy laid out tho city, let
the. streets follow the winding cow paths.
At any rate, the streets ius thoy exist today
urc very crooked and must of them aro
very narrow. This was all right in Revo?
lutionary times, but when the city grow
miles beyond tho Common und spread it?
self out to tho south and west; when busi?
ness centered itself along tbu lower ends
of Washington and Trentont streets, and
when dozens of street car tracks usurped
tho narrow roadways, then the Bostonlans
wished their ancestors bud not stuck so
closely to the cow paths.
Probably no other city on the continent,
was ever so badly allllctcd with a conges?
tion of trnllic as tho Hub haslieon for
many yea: Some of tho most important
street ear linen skirt tho south and east,
cornets ol the Common on Boylston mid
Tremont streets. When I he chango was
made hum hoc. epov.vr to trolley, matters
grew worse. Then tho poles and the tan?
gle of overhead wires made that historic.
breathing spot look liko a pieco of dingy,
green billiard cloth which had become fray?
ed and tuttered around the edges. So after
much wrangling in tho legislature and
courts it w;ls decided tu build the subway
and put the trolley cars underground.
A large portion of the work bus already
lieen accomplished and Boston is delight?
ed with the result. The first thing a Hus?
ton man asks a visitor from Now York,
Chicago or elsewhere is:
"Been through tho subway yet'/ Let's
see?you huven't one in your place, have
you?"
It is, in fact, a triumph of engineering
anil well worth a visit. Then! arc throe
open cut.s where tho trolley curs enter the
subway. One Is out on Tremont street
whore Shawmut avenue comes in. Hero
the tracks from each of those jmorough
fares dive into the tunnel. Another is In
the Public gardens, where the cars com?
ing down Boylston street take tho under?
ground tlip. The third is at tho northerly
end of the subway, just beyond-Hay mar?
ket square and in front of the new Union
terminal railroad station into which the
Fitchburg, Hoston und Maine, Eastern
und other roads run. Theru is u. loop hern
DOSTON'S NEW SUBWAY INCLINE IN THE Plin
LIC ns most of the t rolley lines inako it their
terminus, and, the subway being four
tracked, they disgorge their passengers
and take the back track up town.
Including the inclines or open onto, tho
subway has a total length of 1 miles and
will contain about live miles of track. At
present the branch down Boylston street
along the Common side and the main line
down Tremont to Park street are in oper?
ation. The Shawmut avenue branch and
tho northerly end of the main lino will be
finished within the next eight months.
Ground was broken for the subway in
April, 18115. The sum appropriated was
$7,ii(?0,000 and, wonderful to relate, tho
transit commissioners say that it is proba?
ble the cost will bo about $1,000,000 less
than that sum.
	</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1897-12-15/ed-1/?sp=3&ampq=BOSTON+Boston+SUBWAY+subway&ampst=text&ampr=-0.026,0.088,0.323,0.344,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>
        BOSTON'S UNUSED SUBWAY.
ft) H' VMDBnOltOVSD TBAXBITA TAILURE
j jjv oxvU x. rjtA otice.
Ij aYeople Reniie ta L'se It. Jot as Thfir Wonld
.1' the Hot la tbo Cronna Transit rropwed
J'v fbr Wew .rk Only Keren Per Cent, ef the
M Total Tronic Credited ta the flatmar The
j rreniable rnney TraDI o Lost to It Entirely
Jf Vat tba Condlllem Are nl Farorablr
BbS. Beaten Want, an Klevatrd nallraad Hon,
'sflf "H Before any farther attempt la mado to com'
i V Bait tbli eltr to the building of the proposed
jH underground system of rapid tranalt it would
H be well for every ono Interested to learn somo-
ll thing of the experience which Boston Is now
I lusTlng with Its subway. Boston's subway Is
li'H New York's proposed underground railroad In
L S miniature, excopt that It was constructed for
I H the use of the trolley car lines Instead of being
I V equipped with cars, motors, and power of Its
I H own, and mnnlnir two sets of trains one express
tf( I and one local.
The Boston subway short. That part now
jkVM tense Is less than ft mile In length, and the
KS farts which are under construction or proposed
R M Would add only about another mile to the tun
Hk wr Bet, There lr, perhaps, no finer specimen of
Jl&ampB passenger tunnel work any whero In the world,
aBfYS n ls doubtful -f anymore perfect tunnel
HtjH could Deconstructed.
B9p The tunnel runs under Tremont street, and
HHk Its extensions are to go under Cornhlll, Han
JJ. oxer street, and Washington streot, passing
i right through the denso business and shopping
districts, and thus securing every advantage
I that a road might have If It ran through Broad-
jf Tray, Fourteenth street and Twenty-third street,
i and part of Sixth avenue. And yet. In the face
j ef all these advantages, three months' experi
ence has shown that the Boston subway is not
popular, that people will not go Into It ex-
cept when they have to, and that the subway Is
lv a failure, save so far as It was a necosslty to re-
i'i Have the congestion of traffic on the street.
V XEED OF TUB BUDWAT.
A Bostonlans are proud of the subway. They
ri take strangers to see It, just as they take them
h to see Bunker IIIll Monument; make them ride
vM the length of It back and forth, and call alien
s' I tlon to all its fine foatures and then they keep
I away from it themsolves. Just as thoydofrom
if the monument. That this result ls of tntorest
I V to New Yorkers there can be no doubt. Tho
building of tbo subway growoutof a publloneed
Tfhloh was as absolute and pressing as the need
v ef this city for some addition to Its trafllo
in. facilities.
Hien, about ten years ago. the West End
oet Railway Company began to transform tho
horso car lines of Boston Into electric trot
lines the narrow streets In tho heart of
iton were already choked with tho dally rush
vehicles. Boston has to-day tho most ex
stve and comprehensive electrlo car system
the world. The added cars which wero re
red for tho now service fairly filled
i streets of the little central city
ere they were all concentrated. These
lines eorvo a suburban population of
trly a million persons, and it is possible to
;e a car for any part of the territory covered
.hoot going more thai a quarter of a mllo In
i city. Under a special act of the Lcglsla
e the Boston Transit Commission was ap
nted to devise a suitable means to relieve the
Station.
	</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82016413/1901-07-24/ed-1/?sp=6&ampq=Boston+subway&ampst=text&ampr=-0.249,-0.075,1.499,1.499,0</id>
				<rel>0</rel>
				<text></text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1903-06-21/ed-1/?sp=42&ampq=BOSTON+subway&ampst=text&ampr=-0.302,-487.696,1.604,976.836,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>
	THE MARCH OF IMPROVEMENT IS FAST OBLITERATING MANY OF BOSTONS MOST FAMOUS OLD LANDMARKS
OLD STATIC HOUSE, BOSTON.
To be transformed Into a tunnel station for the subway
BOSTON IMPROVEMENTS.
Historic Landmarks and Crooked
Streets Disappearing.
Boston, June 20.— Within three years the
crooks and turnings and devious wanderings of
Boston's most honored highways and byways
will be nothing more than a memory of the past,
and many of her ancient landmarks will be
wiped out or so altered as to be unrecognizable
to the oldest inhabitant. Slowly and surely the
ancient thoroughfares are being widened,
straightened and bent into the rulerlike lines oC
i rosscut New- York. Philadelphia and Chicago.
Boston is undergoing a transformation below
arid aloft that would cause Benjamin Franklin.
John Hancock, "Warren and Paul Revere *.o rub
their eyes and stare in amazement. Million dol
lar buildings by the dozen, elevated roads, tun
nels and streetcar lines beneath the streets and
under the harbor, swamps and mud Hats filled
for piers and excavated for docks that ac
':;iinodate giant steamers these are the things
they would see.
Along State-st., beneath the spot where the
Boston Massacre occurred, and beneath the his
toric old State House, a tunnel is eating its way
from under the harbor to Scollay Square to con
nect with the present subway by means of
(lights of stairs and elevators, and thence out
side to the busy world. The old Slat- House
itself is to be transformed into a tunnel station
connecting with a subway line also. 
	</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84020274/1904-05-08/ed-1/?sp=57&ampq=New+subway+York&ampr=-0.957,-0.491,2.915,1.552,0</id>
				<rel>0</rel>
				<text></text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88085947/1904-10-27/ed-1/?sp=1&ampq=NEW+OPENED+SUBWAY+YORK&ampr=0.537,0.618,0.201,0.107,0</id>
				<rel>0</rel>
				<text></text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87078082/1910-12-07/ed-1/?sp=3&ampq=Boston+Subway+subway+suicide+SUICIDE&ampr=-0.203,0.2,0.541,0.288,0</id>
				<rel>0</rel>
				<text></text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn97067598/1919-07-21/ed-1/?sp=1&ampq=Boston+BOSTON+Subway&ampr=-0.093%2C0.107%2C0.996%2C0.53%2C0&ampst=text</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>
	Traffic Resumed On Boston
Subway, Elevated And
Surf ace Lines
BOSTON, July 21 Traffic on the surface, 'bway
end elevated lines of Greater Boston was resumt oday
after an interruption of f our days caused by tht yike
of Carmen who demanded an eight hour day and l. in
crease in wages. They were granted an eight hou .g. uy
and an increase in wages, the maximum being 62 '-s
an hour.
DAUGHTER FINDS
FATHER SUICIDE
IN W. CHARLESTON
Henry B. Towne of Stowe commit
ted suicide byslashing his throat with
a razor yesterday at the home of his
daughter, Mrs. Wilfi-cd Hoisington in
West Charleston.
Mr. Towne had been in the habit
of risin glate on Sunday mornings so
his non-appearance at breakfast diri
not cause any anxiety on the part of
his daughter. About eloven o'clock
she decided to cali him and lecciving
no response to her summons entered
the bedroom.
	</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87065526/1963-07-25/ed-1/?sp=3&q=boston+subway&r=-1.02,-0.028,3.04,1.618,0</id>
				<rel>0</rel>
				<text></text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn79000083/1961-11-18/ed-1/?sp=3&q=boston+subway&st=text&r=-0.297,-0.08,1.593,1.593,0</id>
				<rel>0</rel>
				<text></text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83004278/1961-09-27/ed-1/?sp=4&q=boston+subway&st=text&r=0.655,0.339,0.203,0.216,0</id>
				<rel>0</rel>
				<text></text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86075229/1955-02-24/ed-1/?sp=2&q=boston+subway&st=text&r=-0.262,-0.123,1.524,1.524,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text> The first subway opened in
Boston in 1897.
	</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85053044/1952-01-04/ed-1/?sp=4&q=boston+subway&st=text&r=0.211,0.332,0.705,0.705,0</id>
				<rel>0</rel>
				<text></text>
			</result>
		</results>
	</topic> – TOPIC 2(10 + 5)
  
	<topic>
		<id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-eiffel-tower/selected-articles</id>
		<results>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83025121/1889-04-02/ed-1/?sp=8&q=Eiffel+Tower+France+French+Paris+Worlds+Fair&st=text&r=-0.283,-0.078,1.566,1.566,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>THE EIFFEL TOWER
A Msht and Sensation for lisitor to
1arls
In view of the assurance of a
creditable representation of Hawaii
both in productions and person
agesat the Universal Exhibition of
this year in Paris a few facts rela
tive to the EiffeUower culled from
a late English paper may be of local
interest
The tower is named after its pro
jector Mr Eiffel now President of
the French Association of Engineers
He is famed in part -for the design
ing of a great bridge at Bordeaux
Although the Eiffel tower was orig
inally the conception mainly of an
ambition likened to that of Ameri
cans by the English paper referred
to for having the highest structure
in the world it was also early as
sumed that it would have uses in the
interest of science It is claimed
and anticipated that it will be very
raluable for observatory purposes
owing to the perfect clearness of the
air at its summit
The tower is to be one thousand
feet in height At the date of the
description here drawn upon it had
attained an altitude of 738 feet or
162 feet higher than any other build
ing on earth There were 180 men
employed then in its construction
100 preparing the lifts at the base
and 80 riveting the perfectly fitted
parts at top To avoid fatiguing the
workmen aloft in descending several
times a day for food a restaurant is
fitted up at a height of about 400
feet There are to bo four perman
ent restaurants for the refreshment
of visitors on the first stage of the
tower</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn91068084/1889-04-26/ed-1/?sp=5&q=Eiffel+Tower+Paris+Exhibition+1000+Feet+High+France+French+Worlds+Fair&st=text&r=-0.335,-0.083,1.669,1.669,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>NEARLY 1000 FEET HIG&
The Great Eiffel Tower at the
Paris Exposition.
How the Colossal Structure, Just
Completed, was Erected.
The great Eiffel tower at the Paris Exhi
bition has just been completed, and a de
scription of the colossal structure, with an
account of the way it was built, and a sketch
of its constructor, will bo appropriate at this
time. It is scarcely necessary to say that the
U
mm

Cologne
Cathedral,
511 ft.
The Eiffel Tower,
9S4 ft. The Great
Pyramid,
480 ft.
Eiffel tower is by far the highest structure in
the world. It presents a decidedly unique ap
pearance, too in general outline not unlike a
stack of four gigantic muskets with their
butts well and solidly spread and their bay
onets joining at their tips.
The Eiffel tower stands in the Champ de
Mars, almost on the left bank of the river
Seine, just in the rear of the Quai d'Orsay,
and in fact a part of its foundation is sunk
through an old arm of the river, which lias
been filled in these many years. Its base
covers a plot of ground 328 feet square, or
nearly two and a half acres in extent.
GUSTAVF. EIFFEL.
It Ls really at the base a group of four tow
ers, each nearly fifty feet square, placed at
the corners of the plot of ground, and in
clining toward each other as they rise at an
angle of fifty-four degrees. Each tower con
sists of four columns, bound together by
trusswork, and each column rests on a
masonry pier which is so built that the weight
of the column rests upon it squarely and not
at an ancle.
As the tower is 0S4 feet high. it will be
seen that the matter of providing a solid
foundation was one of great importance.
There was a lot of boring and digging befon
the spot upon which the tower stands was
finally selected.
The foundation rests upon a thick stratum
of sand and gravel. It may be well to say.
for the benefit of those who think sand is a
rather treacherous sort f ground, that a bed
of sand and gravel, away under ground, is
pretty solid stuff. One of the towers of the
Brooklyn Bridge rests on that sort of base.
The foundations of the two piers of the Eiffel
tower farthest from the Seine rest on sand
and gravel about twenty-five feet below the
surface of the ground. These foundations
were laid in open excavations, and consist
first of great solid platforms of beton, six
feet thick, and next of four stone piers which
rise to the surface to receive the iron col
umns. The foundations for the two piers nearest
the river were not so easily laid. It was
necessary to go thirty-five feet below the
surface of the ground, end this was sixteen
feet under water. So caissons had to be
used, as they were in building the Brooklyn
Bridge piers.
A caisson is in effect simply an enormous
iron box, without any cover, turned upside
down. The method of using it is to dig the
earth out from under it and allow it to
gradually settle as the excavation pro
gresses, meanwhile building the pier on top.
When the required depth is reached the cais
a .n itself is filled up with the beton, and it
forms the bottom layer of it a foundation.
A shaft is left running through the pier
auove for entrance and exit as the work goes
on, and the air in the caisson and shaft is
compressed to whatever is necessary to keep
the water out of the bottom. It is the prin
ciple of the diving bell modified.
Work on the foundations was begun on
January 28, 1887, and at the end of June they
were completed. Then began the labor of
setting up the innumerable pieces of iron of
which the tower is composed, and it went on
at a vapid rate, for each individual piece
came from the works of M. Eiffel, at Leval-lois-Pere
cut to its exact dimensions, fitted
and drilled, so that no modification was neces
sary at the place of operations. Up to a
height of about fifty feet the workmen re
quired no scaffolding to work upon, as each
pier supported itself, although each leaned
toward the others. Then an artificial support
had to le provided, as above that height, un
til the first platform was reached, the center
of gravity of each pier would fall outside of
the base.
And so piece by piece the towers grew,
and at length reached a height of 140 feet.
Then four enormous horizontal trusses were
put in place to connect the four piers. These
were nearly 140 feet long and weighed a
good many tons, and hi order to place them
in position it was necessary to erect an ex
tensive false work, or scaffolding. "When
these trusses were in position, and the con
necting beams to form a flooring were in
place, the workmen ha1 a great solid plat
form, nearly 15U feet above the ground and
upward of 1 oJ feet square, to work upon.
These four inclined piers and the four big
connecting trusses form the solid groundwork
of the tower. There is nothing particularly
unique in the detail of construction. The
work is simply a system of trusses and braces,
in which the material is so placwd as to make
a strong and light structure. The four great
arches which rise between the piers, imme
diately under the great horizontal trusses,
are largely ornamental in character. They
serve to round off what would otherwise be
an angular outline, but do not support any of
the weight of the structure.
Above the lower platform two four-corner
piers incline toward each other at a
sharper angle. The iron columns are lighter
and the spaces in the system of bracing are
larger. High above the first platform, nearly
400 feet from the ground, a second series of
horizontal trusses binds the four piers to
gether and forms the basis for a second land
ing. These two platforms are glorious places
St. Peter's,
433 ft. Rouen
Cathedral,
470 ft.
Statue of Wash- Column
Liberty, ington Vendome,
301 ft. Monument, 148 ft.
500 ft.
from which to view the city of Paris. They
are so large that even very timid persons
standing on them will lose all fear. The
lower one is nearly half an acre in extent
while the upper one is about one-third that
size. From the platform a view of the coun
try for forty miles around may be obtained.
Above the second platform the four corner
piers gradually approach each other and at
length unite in one pier, at the top of which,
nearty a fifth of a mile from the ground,
there is a covered observatory, and above
this rises a slender mast. Doubtless many
thousand people will see Paris and ever so many
square miles of surrounding country from the
observatory during the summer. They will
not have to walk up, for a gigantic elevator
runs up through one of the piers to the very
top. This elevator is of peculiar construction,
for the carriage or truck, travels upward on
a spiral track, while the car itself rises
vertically, or rather as nearly vertically as
the angle of the pier will allow.
While the Eiffel tower was a stupendous
conception, and will stand as completed
the marvel of modern engineering, no new
principles are involved in its construction.
In fact, to an engineer, the most wonderful
thing about the tower is its simplicity. The
way for the Eiffel tower, both in conception
and execution, was paved, after a fashion,
by the work on the Garobit viaduct and the
Taraes bridge, both of which were built by
Eiffel. In fact, the construction of bridges
and viaducts, without the use of scaffolding or
false work, by making the several parts
balance themselves as the work progresses,
owes much to this French engineer.
Gustavo Eiffel is a master of construction.
It is said of him that he combines within
himself the practical knowledge of the Eng
lish engineer, the audacity of the American
and the science and theories of the French
man. He was born at Dijon, France, in 1S32,
and was educated at the Central School of
Sciences and Arts. He it was who first made
practical use of compressed ah in cassions in
the building of bridge foundations, in the
erection of the great bridge at Bordeaux.
TOP OF THE TOWER.
M. Eiffel has been a busy man, indeed, these
many years, but he found time, when the
statue of Liberty Enlightening the World was
to be set up in New ork Harbor, to design
the skeleton framework which support the
gigantic figure and at the same time firmly
holds it to the granite pier on which it stands.
A glance at the illustration will show to
what extent the Eiffel tower overshadows all
the famous tall structures of the world. In
comparison with its 984 feet Cheops is dwarfed
at 40. The Washington Monument is little
less than 500 feet high, and the point of .he
flame of Liberty's torch in New- York Harbor
rises barely 300 feet in the air.
The fees for ascending the Eiffel tower are
five francs (1) to the cop, three francs
(sixty cents) to the second platform an 1 two
francs (forty cents) t. the first. </text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87060190/1889-05-07/ed-1/?sp=4&q=Eiffel+Tower+Paris+France+French+Expo+Exhibition+Worlds+Fair</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>BASE OF EIFFEL TOWER,
ia tho middlo, and is surrounded by build
ings containing exhibitions of flue arts,
boUos lettres, tho liberal arts, and various
departments of industry.
Those buildings stand on parallel lines and
ore crossed in their axis by a high gallery
manaounted by a doma which leads to th
hatt of machinery. Tho cost of tho build
ings in tho Champs do Mars, exclusivo of tho
Mffel tower, has been about (4,000,000, and
it is intended that they shall remain as per
aaaent structures. The total outlay author
ised for tho entire exposition U 38,600,000, of
wttch $000,000 is hold aa a rcerve fund.
The earthworks required a removal of
700,000 cubic foot. Tke drains and water
pipes of the Camps do Mars were lengthened
hf about two miles, and more than 40,009
ems of iron and steel wero u&ed by the
holders. The hall of machinery is 1,309 feet
long and 150 feet high, covered with a roof
f iron, wood and glass, having a span of
380 feet in tho clear, the greatest ever at
tempted. A gullory extends around tke in
terior for the display of tho lighter classes of
machinery and from end to end run four un
ferofcen linos of shafting for distributing the
Beotivo power. Tho powor is dorived from a
proup of steam engines placed in one of
the touts, tho bollors of which transform
into steam forty tons of wator per hour.
The total energy is about 400 horse power.
TJio chief architectural feature of the ex
position is, of course, tho Eiffel tower, as
wore the Crystal Palace at London In 1851,
the iron lighthouse at Paris in 1807, tho groat
THE EIFFEL TOWZ& VBOX THE BEINK
rotunda at Vionna in 1873, and the Trocadero
palace at Paris in 1878. This is the loftiest
structure eyer rahedjjy Iman, being about
064 feet high. The Washington monumont
now stands second, 55.5 feet. The Cologno
cathedral is 501 feot. Tho tower of Babol
was probably CS0 high. Moro than 7,000
tons of metal were us?d in building tho
Eiffel tower. Tho first sod was turned in
excavation for its foundation on January
28, 1887, and the whole work was completed
on March 31, 1889.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85033162/1900-05-18/ed-1/?sp=3&q=Paris+Exposition&st=text&r=0.311,-0.049,0.165,0.176,0</id>
				<rel>0</rel>
				<text></text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85032018/1894-01-31/ed-1/?sp=15&q=Eiffel+Tower+Paris+France+French+Worlds+Fair+1900+Exhibition&st=text&r=0.049,0.411,0.455,0.485,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>tj Happily all Paris is not so pessi
mistic as my friend, and the architects
are busy with their plans. All the
ground comprised in the exhibition of
'89 is to be included, as well as the por
tion of Cour la Heine that will inclose
the Palais 1' Industrie and its surround
ing gardens. We are to have an addi
tional bridge across the Seine which
will open a vista from the Place de la
Concorde straight through to the palace
of electricity, which is to be the cen
tral feature. Our rulers are greatly
bored about the Eiffel tower; but as
the concession was granted for twenty
years it has got to stand; but the arch
itects say consolingly that the 7 will
try and hide it as much as possible.
The sight of it vexes poetio souls,
and Francois Coppee, the author, who
is, by way of being, sthetio, wrote
a formal protest to the government at
the time of its erection to request that
the plan should not be carried out on
the ground that the Eiffel tower, being
ugly and ungainly, and furthermore
being visible from his windows, inter
fered with his flow of inspiration.
However, the tower was built never
theless, and, although we are deadly
tired of seeing it about, Coppee con
tinues to write, so evidently his flow
ol inspiration was only impeded and
not permanently plugged up. Further
more, we are to have a branch exhibit
at Versailles, which will rouse that
sleepy little town from its chief ou
pation of listening to the grass grow
ing in the streets. In the splendid
park of Versailles, on either side of
the grand canal, is to be the retro
spective history of gardens throughout
the ages.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83040198/1899-02-03/ed-1/?sp=7&q=Eiffel+Tower+France+French+Paris+Exhibition+Worlds+Fair+Ladder+Clouds</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>A LADDER FROM THE CLOUDS
Bach Will Be the Appearance of the
Eiffel Tower of Parts When
Painted.
The Eiffel tower, say the gentlemen
of esthetic temperament, must go.
The Eiffel tower, say the gentlemen
who know the law, must stay for some
years yet. The Eiffel tower, say the
esthetes. Is ugly, discouraging to the
eye and an all-round nightmare. "Scaf
fold I cries the carper. "Down with it
It has no place in esthetic Paris,"
"Impossible! objects the law. "When
the company took a lease of it they
got it for a term of 20 years.. You
can't break the lease, and the time is
nowhere up.
"But, urges the esthete, "look at
the shape, look at the size, look at the
color! Is not the whole thing hideous"?
If we can't destroy it we can at least
improve it and lessen the offense to
our senses."
And so the Eiffel tower is going to be
metamorphosed. It has. been in color
a reddish brown, and it is the color to
which the gentlemen with the fine ideas
have long objected. They have called
the tower a shameless creation and re
peatedly ridiculed the commonplace
tone of hue. And now they have pre
v ailed, and the lower is going to be a
thing of beauty, so far as that goes.
Silver white is the color agreed upon,
and it is urged that when the army of
workmen have finished their painting
the huge structure will look really not
so bad after all. Ilalf a hundred men
will be employed on the building, work
ing hard every day for two months.
And 50,000 kilogrammes of paint will
be used up before the Eiffel tower has
finally lost its brickdust coat and finds
itself arrayed in the poetic covering
which the esthetes have advised. Two
coats of paint will be applied and the
brushes will be busy.
It has been objected that the tbwer
has always had the appearance or hav
ing been cast up in inartistic form by
a careless earth. The tower has seemed
to rise awkwardly from the ground,
the critical have said. Why not give
it such an arrangement as would sug
gest the idea of dropping from the
clouds? That would be a pleasing fan
cy, and if the huge tower were lighted
at regular intervals it would present a
picture as of a brilliant creature of the
clouds, and all the world would be lost
in admiration. These plans were sug
gested when the exposition of 1900 were
tinder discussion, and they have been
adopted. A ladder from the clouds.
That was tbe idea. 'And with that the
esthetic taste, was forced to be sat
isfied.
The Eiffel tower has long been the
universal bed lamp of Paris. The great
candle in the top would be sadly miss-d,
even by those who have fought agair.&t
the continuance of the structure. That
ever-swaying lantern is one of the won
ders of the French capital. Y. Her
aid.
Kicked All Around.
A correspondence is being published
In the Times on the subject of "French
Feeling Toward Englishmen." A Mr.
Jackson has written to that paper to
repeat that at Caen recently a student
went out of his way to publiely insult
Great Britain. As a boy I was first for
some years at school in Paris.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1900-05-20/ed-1/?sp=43&q=Feet+Tower+Eiffel+Paris+France+French+Worlds+Fair+Exhibition&st=text&r=0.213,0.783,0.517,0.551,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>way from the Eiffel Tower
Ml M
•i" first ha'.f c* the left line is the Palace of
H;srs and Metallurgy. Like all the other build
fc?T= en the Charrr de Mars, it is constructed
ti iron, cover*"? with wooden laths and faced
r
with plastf r. Th-> ornamentation is extremely
_.
light, white being the prevailing tone. The dome
consists of an imrr.vns-; tiara resplendent in imi
taticn precious stune:-— a novel and nappy form
cf decoration. The second half, leading to the
Pu.iac-e of Electricity, is occupied by the Palace
tf Threads and Textile Fabrics. It consists of a
!:r.e of raJ>'-i arches, forming the outside of a
covered gallery, given up to restaurants, some
thing similar to the constructions that were here
in the same place in l vV A fine central porch
It is
I
_ iring
_.
th that of Let I i
ad In

En-
ration is in good
icted
th< rin all their
these two
THE GREAT FOUNTAIN.
At the end of the grounds and joining these
t*o wisp, is the Palace of Electricity, preceded
ty the EC'Cum-nta! fountain, or Chateau d'Eau.
The latter is one of the principal decorative sub
>-r.s of the Champ de ilars. It is composed of
vast semicircular alcove LOB f eel wide by 30
i«t deep, containing a series of immense basins
iJTanged in amphitheatre form, from which
Eiects cf water £cw and fall in cascades into a
T« larger basin at Coot cf the fountain. The
quantity cf water employed is at the rate of
*^*i,*Mi litres _.. bear. la the lar^e basin is
NEW YORK TRIBUNE tout HTRATED BUPPLBMENT.
HumanuJ%T UP r32r 32 feet hi h representing
to the F,,; db Fro^" marching onward
the cenfr^ o™ A l!POttO has been bu »t behind
the central cascade, accessible to visitors.
THE PALACE OF ELECTRICITY.
Immediately behind the Chateau d'Eau is the
Palace of Electricity, which l a incontestably the
chief and most interesting portion of the whole
exhibition. The chief aim in its construction
has been to hide the straight plainness of the
Gallery of Machines of ISS9. therefore the roof
has been raised to the height of 202 feet, form-
IB* a crown to the edifice. its front, which is In
repousse zinc worked like lace, consists of nine
bays provided with multicolored decorations.
transparent ceramics and stained glass, in har
moniously blended tones. The wings of the pal
ace, JIM feet by 131 feet, contain the machines
which supply electrical power to the exhibition.
The building Is illuminated by 5.000 variegated
PAVILIONS AT THE FEET OV THE EIFFEL TOWER.
S arc lamps with col
four arc lamps with re
				</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059523/1903-10-25/ed-1/?sp=24&q=Eiffel+Tower+Doomed+Rocks+Wind+Paris+France+French+Gustav</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>THE Eiffel Tower must come down.
The authorities of Paris have so decreed.
This iron spire, the tallest structure in the
world, and the engineering feat of the last cen
tury, \.i regarded as a dangerous plaything.
When a high wind blows from the south the great
ribbed structure trembles like a frightened horse.
But let a stiff breeze come bowling down from the
north and the tower vibrates until the china rattles in
the cafes, and to those in the observatory at the apex the
sensation is that of a ship fossed by heavy seas.
The fact that the tower is more'sensitive to a wind
from the north than from the south is regarded as proof
of the structural weakness, and from this springs the
theory of danger of collapse.
It is almost twenty years since Gustav Eiffel began
the work of building his sky-scraper. The mark of com
pletion was set for 1889, Exposition year, and on March 31
of that year the tower was thrown open to the public. It
wa« the leading attraction of the big show, and it has
not since ceased to attract attention and coin.
The cost of building the structure was more than
$1,000,000. Of that amount the French government appro
priated $29L',000. Eiffel supplied the remainder, trusting
for his reimbursement to the receipts from admission fees
and other sources.
In this he was not uisappolnted, as the profits of the
first year were almost sufficient to make him whole.
The lease held by Eiffel will expire in next March, and
then, if the present plans of the city fathers are realized,
the work of razing the unique structure will be started.
The plan is to sell the tower to the highest bidder, the
purchaser to be given a certain time in which to remove
what Paris regards as almost a public menace.
Except as a curio and an Investment for its builder,
the tower has been somewhat of a failure.
Much was expected in the scientific world from the
metaphorical observatory, with its physical and biological
laboratories, all 954 feet above ground. But little has
come of this, the enterprise having taken on a rather
commercial aspect.
The Eiffel Tower will ever be considered a colossa*
feat of engineering.
Tlhese Stria! Ihxean F®ds ire nsudhes hM
.'v_V- Ir 'mJf.A?j -i?'^^t Vk^T*i^*v*
THE beanstalk up which Jack, the Giant Killer,
climbed to fame has been sung and pictured until
even little Emma and Annie and Jeannette and
Joe, sprawled there on the nursery floor, can tell
of its sturdy trunk, of its stout, ladder-like branches, of
Its leathery leaves, which the eager hands of their hero.
Jack, could not crush, though he clutched them ever so
tightly.
They can tell you that this fabled beanstalk was so
tall that "Oo! you jest couldn't see the top uv it, so you
couldn't."
DRINKERS IN TWO CLASSES
==Mlsery and L,Mxtuiry==
BOTH CLAIM THEIR VICTIMS OF LIQUOR
LONDON, August 17.
WOMEN who drink are classified by the experts
into two sections—misery drinkers and luxury
drinkers.
Speaking broadly, the misery drinkers come
from the very poor, the luxury drinkers from the rich.
But whatever the cause which first sends them to drink
the ultimate results are the same—a falling birth-rate, a
rising death-rate among infants and the physical degen
eration of the race.
Dr. Claye Shaw, a recognized authority, made it clear,
in discussing the matter recently, that the evil is not con
fined to the lowest order of society.
"My experience," he said, "is that among women of
fashion, women who have nothing to do but to amusa
themselves, there l a a growing tendency to take alco
holic stimulants, and the ill effects of that, both upon the
•women themselves and upon their children, are often very
■erlous
"There is a great deal of private drinking. I know
towns where it is a common thing for young girls to go to
a private counter in a confectioners shop and take a
glass or two of champagne or a glass or two of port.
"There are confectioners' shops in London where wo
men of position do the same thing. And at home there is
•adly too much nipping of spirits in private. It does not
etop at that. Many women drink cologne, many use mor
phia.
"Jt is the result of high living, and an emotional,
unnatural, excited way of life. All this leads to personal
demoralization and the weakening of character. Some
times it is a step towards the divorce court.
"The trouble is that the women have nothing to do
nothing to occupy their minds. The happiest marriages
The lower section consists of four columns resting
upon masonry 85 feet square and 30 feet high. These
curve toward each other, so that they unite as a slnglo
column 620 feet above the ground.
PARIS, October 10.
There are platforms at the 189, 380 and 906 feet levels,
reached by elevators as well as by Btairs. Beyond the
third platform a spiral staircase, which is not open to the
public, ascends to the top of the tower.
On the first platform, which has a floor space of 38,000
Bquare feet, or nearly an acre, there were four restau
rants at the time of the Exposition, and refreshments are
Btill served there.
The view from the top of the tower extends eight y
flve miles on a clear day. At night a searchlight gleams
from the eminence.
Seven thousand tens of iron were used in building the
Eiffel Tower.
Gustav Eiffel made a long leap over precedent when
he planned and built the spiral skeleton of Iron which
made him rich and famous.
The ambition of the Egyptians to pierce the sky with
pyramids carried them less than half as high as this
French engineer went on a comparatively fragile founda
tion.
The pyramid of Cheops 13 only 486 feet high; that of
Cephrenes 456 feet.
The best that Rome can do, with all her boasted
achievements in lofty architecture, is to point to the dome
of St. Peter's—a paltry 448 feet above ground.
London steps into third place in these Old World ver
tical achievements with her St. Pauls dome—36s feet up.
Campanile, the famous leaning tower at Pisa, did not
win fame because of the height of its arcaded colonnades
bo much as because of its obliquity, and yet when we are
told that this tower is thirteen feet out of plumb we
learn in the same breath that it is 179 feet high!
Stepping over to the New World to complete the table
of comparisons more ambitious figures are encountered,
and yet our best achievements are as pigmies in the
shadow of the tower that Eiffel built.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1907-03-10/ed-1/?sp=47&q=Eiffel+Tower+Gustav+Paris+France+French+Republic</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>France Pranceher her fron frontiers fro1Zjers
tiers jers her chains clzaillsof clzaillsoffortresses of offortresses
fortresses and her herseaboard herscaboardsllch
seaboard scaboardsllch such Is Isto isto
to be the I further furthermission furthermisJion
mission of Ithc the fa famous famOlls
mOlls Eiffel Tower Toweri Towerof
i of Paris ParisThis Par J JThis
This struct strllcillrc strllcillrcere lire
4 e ere r e c t c d a as s the thechief thechief
chief curiosity of ofthe ofthe
the Paris Exposi Exposition E 4posi 4position
tion has outlived outlivedits
its 11 usefulness in other respects and has hasbeen hasbeen
been made the central point of the great greatwireless greatwireless
wireless signal system of the French army armyand armyand
and navy
From the top of the tower which is
984 feet from the ground roll1td officials of the thearmy thearmy
army may direct military operations op ratio1Zs in any anyLift allYLftt
Lift up your eyes and behold them that come from fromthe tromthe
the NorthJer aclll 0 0URLNG 0D
FlUNG the army manoeuvres last fall fallthe fallthe
D the various corps were directed from fromthe fromthe
the now station Later fleet movements movementsin mO mcnts mcntsin
in the Englislrchannel El lis1 chRnnel and the Mediter Mediterranean M diter diterranean
ranean wore ordered ord 6dwithout without a hitch in the samo samoway sarnotvaJr
way wayQuite Quite lecently the scope scoP of communication communicationfirm comunicatio1f
firm f m the tower towmlms has been Cxf rlendc1 ended so that no nOtY nOtYmessages v vmessages
messages are exchanged e changed with London and Ber Berlin Berlin
lin on the one onG side and with Tunis and Algiers Algierson Algierionthe
on onthe the African coast on the other otherTte otherThe
The work of equipping it for signal pur purposes purposes
poses is now going on and it is expected to in inEtal instal
Etal there the most complete coml lete system s stem of wire wireless wireleastelcir8P1ly
less leastelcir8P1ly tdegrapny in the thewodd thewoddne world worldThe
The French Frenchare are pleased with the idea of 1C 1Cbining re retaining
taining the architectural curiosity curiosi ty and their theirjeamty tbcirFanity
jeamty is tickled hy the plan to make it the theriost theost
riost ost wonderful war eye on the globe globeIndeed glober
r Indeed the enthusiastic people pcoJ le confidently confidentlysrpect confidentlyb
b srpect ect in a short time tim to see 5e airships arriving arrivingt
1t t and nd departing from this great steel stom stomfcn stomin
fcn airship airshipstntion station nearly 1000 feet above earth earthBuilt earth1nt
Built 1nt by the th famous engineer Gustavo Eif Eifr Eifrrr
r
rrr I
part of ortlze the Republic and even for consider considerable cOlZsijerable
able distances ovei tle tile frontier in adjolnlng adjolnlngcountries adj illi1lg illi1lgcOlilltries
countries Its naval fleets In the thelYledi thelYledierrmzetlll Medi Mediterranean
terranean errmzetlll the Bay Ba of Biscay the English EnglishChannel EllglishClza1l1zel
Channel the North Sea or the Baltic B ltic will willbe willbc
be In constant touch with the directing directingauthorities directilZgauthorities
authorities In Paris ParisShould ParisShould
Should France and England become becomeallies becolleallies
allies in some future conflict direct com communication commtl1licat
mtl1licat munication on with London can be maintained maintainedfrom mailltailledfrom
from the Eiffel Tower Southward from fromit
it waves of warning anJtSfypmmand Jm1lZmzd will willfloat j
float into d Algeria 19cria and Tunis From this rc rcmarkable rcmarkable
markable tower may issue orders that wilt wiltchange willdt willdtczange
change the 7i of Europe v vfel
czange map ap i iI iI iIel I I
fel the tower was completed in March 1889 lSS9jn lSS9jntime in intime
time to tOSCITe serve as 13 one of the notable features featur 5J of ofthe oftlte
the exposition of that year ear It was the loading loadingattraction leallingattraction
attraction of that big show and has never neversince neversinceceased since sinceceased
ceased to draw visitors and coin coinIt coinIt
It cost considerably over 1000000 to build buildtho buildtho
tho tower for which 7000 tons of metal were wereused wereused
used Of the cost 292000 was voted by tha thagovernment thlgovernmont
government while the engineer supplied the therest thereat
rest The profits for 1SS9 alone nearly paid nid tha thacost thacost
cost
Some idea of its height height984 984 fcot feotway niay be begained begained
gained from a comparison with other structures structuresof
of the world Tho Washington Monument at atWashington atVashington
Washington D C is 555 feet tall the broad broadbrimmed broadbrimmed
brimmed hat of William Penn on Philadel Philadelphias Philadelphias
phias City Hall is 547 feet above the pave pavement pavement
ment the dome of St Peters in Rome rises risesto risesto
to only 448 feet while the great pyramid of ofCheops ofCheops
Cheops is but 486 feet high highFrom highFrom
From the top of the Eiffel Tower on onjlclear onjlclearday tclear tclearday
day one can see about eightyfive mUei At Atnight Atni
night ni ht a searchlight from this eminence stabs the thesurrounding thesurrounding
surrounding darkness darknessAt darknessAt
At its base this wonderful tower covers coversnearly coversnnarb
nearly twc and a half acres of ground Its
mt tmTf iY Wf Wflower
lower section consists of four builtup iron col columns c ll llumns
umns each of which consists of four smaller smallercolumns smaUercolumns
columns resting on masonry piers piersSpringing piersSpringin
Springing gracefully upward tho th four fourmain IOlrmain
main columns curve toward each other until
020 feet above the surface they join in si single singlecolumij singlecolum
columij colum Above this the long needle of the thetower thetocr
tower rises rie 3G4 feet higher higherAt1 higherAtlS0
At1 AtlS0 ISO feet at 3SO feet and again a ain at 006 006feet 908feet
feet there are platforms which are reached by byelevators byelevators
elevators as well as by b stairs stairsFrom stairsFrom
From the t e highest highcstplatform platform a winding stair stairway stairway
way climbs to the very pinnacle of the struc structure strueture
ture but this part has never been open to the thepublic theBublic
public publicWhen
When qen these different platforms are can canverted CQ CQverted
verted in into tn airship stations the French will in indeed</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1907-05-18/ed-1/?sp=26&q=Dangerous+Painting+World+Eiffel+Tower+Paris+France+French+Republic+Gustav&st=text&r=0.1,0.034,1.119,1.119,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>Height of the Great Tower
as Compared to Some of
the World's Tallest
Structures.
Special Correspondence of The Star.
PARIS, May A, 1907.
A painter has Just fallen from the Eiffel
Tower. Four more men must fall to make
the awful average of the most dangerous
painting Job in the world?repeated every
six years only.
They are repainting the Eiffel Tower,
and all Paris is concerned about the color,
on which depends whether the gigantic
mass of iron shall be the eyesore or the
glory of the capital.
Its first shade was "dead leaf," In 1889.
When the sun lit it up to hazy golden with
an unreal effect of Jeweler's fragility, even
the artists who now corse it admitted that
the Eiffel Tower had its nobility.
In 1896, after immense discussion, they
repainted It orange, magnetic currents
even more than light and weather having
turned it to a dingy chocolate, heavy and
obtrusive. In strong sun the orange
showed gleaming copper or red gold. Oscar
Wilde declared It magnificent. Puvis de
Chavannes threatened to blow It up with
dynamite. From this period dated the bad
name the tower acquired as a colossal
piece of engineering vulgarity, usurping
the artistic note of Paris.
Then, for the exposition, they painted it
"sun color." In bright lights the tower
became a thing of glory once again.
"All Depends Upon the Faint."
"All depends upon the paint!" declares
the city's architect, Bouyard, "a fact
which shows the utter inartistic character
of the Titan 1^3 intruder. The pyramids ol
Egypt were originally cased with gleaming
marble; but its present lack does not
detract from the artistic appropriateness
of the pyramids to their situation!"
The tower gleamed sun color seven years
agoi But the atmospheric electricity received
every hour since then by such an
unprecedented mass of iron reaching into
the air so high is Incalculable. Conducting
tubes a foot and a half in diameter
lead it down the four niles to flftv feet be
low the water-bearing stratum; but the
effect on the paint la there for every one
to see. It does not crack the paint off.
The paint simply disappears, leaving the
ugly chocolate, the dingy brown of the
oxidising iron.
It Is the tower's way of "calling for new
victims. Fifty painters, working continuously
together, take three months to do a
ingle coat Few tourists realise- the immense
proportions of the tower, but
Parisian!, by experience, show you a peculiar
phenomenon of Its deceptive symmetry.
They take you In a cab close to the
tower. It looks heavy and chunky. It
seems sinking into the earth from lU
weight. Half a mile distant from that
oab the tower grows higher and slenderer.
It seems to lift Itself from the earth, like
a person rising from his knees. "Why, It's
bigger than before!" you say. At a mil*
distant-It seems quite as near. The river
boats ttmt flit beside It now look tiny. The
buildings round about are growing small.
But the tower grows! Then at two miles?
from the heights above Passy?It appears
A 4kin? A# litfhtnMa hl alAn^nrAf
Efc IIIIUB Vi u fc?v? gutiUVBWi ?and
more open In Its lacework than when
you gaped at its foot almost disappointed!
In a country town thirty miles from
Paris I have sat at night and watched Its
leaxchltsht!
Some Comparisons.
Tou think Niagara Falls are high? They
are 105 feet, and St. Paul's Cathedral, Lon- 1
don. is 404 feet. Niagara Falls could de
scend from below St. Paul's dome. Now
place St. Paul's beside the Eiffel tower. It
reaches only to the second platform of the
tower?the real beginning of its slender
shaftl
Place the Eiffel tower beside the greatest
buildings of the world. The great pyramid
does not reach to Its Intermediate platform.
Neither does the spire of the Cologne 1
Cathedral.
Only one 'set of buildings, nevertheless,
are higher than the Cologne Cathedral
Bplre. They are the sky-scrapers of American
dtles, the tallest actually existing being,
say, 6S6 feet high. It would not reach to
the tower's intermediate platform, either.
The loftiest masonry construction In the
world is to be the Singer building extension,
at the corner of Liberty street and
Broadway, New Torlc. Beating any other J i
American sky-scraper by 57 feet, it will i
stick 612 feet into the air. And yet even j
It will not reach to the Eiffel tower's inter- i
mediate platform 1
You can easily detect this intermediate i
platform half way up the slender shaft of 3
the Eiffel tower. In the nearer photographs j
It shows for what it is?a mere platform
for styftlng passengers from one set of ele- t
vators to another, built In the center of the 1
the time you git left. This yere man. Bob
Hampton, Is my prisoner, an' I'll take him
to Cheyenne. If I have ter brain every tough t
in Glencaid to do It. Thet's me, gents." 1
"Oh, come oft; you can't run your notions j
igin the whole blame moral sentiment of c
this camp." c
"Moral sentiment! I'm backln' up the t
aw, not moral sentiment, ye cross-eyed c
jeer-slinger, an' if ye try edgin' up ther l
mother stfep I'll plug you with this '45.' c
There was a minute or hesitancy while i
iie men below conferred, the marshal f
ooking contemptuously down upon them, c
lis revolver gleaming ominously in the v
lght. Evidently the group hated to go back
without the prisoner. j
"Oh, come on. Buck, show a little hoss i<
fense." the leader sang out "We've got c
>very feller in camp along with us, an' 1
:here ain't no show fer the two o' ye to t
lold out against that sort of an outfit." 8
Mason smiled and patted the barrel of hia
-olt-
"Oh. go to biases! wnen i want any aa- t
rice, Jimmie, I'U send fer ye."
Some one flred, the ball. digging up the f
10ft earth at the marshal's feet, and fling-
ng it in a blinding cloud into Hampton's f
>yes. Mason's answer was a sudden fusi-
ade. which sent the crowd flying helter- 8
skelter into the underbrush. One among
hem staggered and half fell, yet succeeded
Wmcelf nnt nf slffht V
"Great Scott, If I don't believe I winged
Fanjes!" the shooter remarked cheerfully,
-eaching back Into his pocket for more f
cartridges. "Maybe them boys will be a
)lt more keerful If they once onderstand v
hey're up agin the real thing. Well, per-
laps I better skin down, fer I reckon It's
table ter be rifles next" t
It was rifles next, and the "wincing" of
US PAINTING JOE
EIFFEL TOWER C
A Comparison of the Relative Heigl
Build
The Great Pyramid. 480 ft. Wanhington Monument,
ftt. Paul'*, 404 ft. Blackpool Tower, 516 ft.
Monument, 202 ft. Nelaon
shaft and not extending to Its exterior.
In photographs of the tower at a greater
distance It appears more clearly?almost
like a story. And it is 647 feet from the
ground.
High Above the Ground.
The third platform?which looks like the
brim of a hat at the top?is 911 feet from
the ground. Niagara, with a suspension
bridge 100 feet high over it, could easily
fall between it and the intermediate platform?above
the top of the Singer extension;
while the true top of the tower is still
74 feet higher!
VIotroxA Poll- 0
a tu^ui u. i- ano nuuiu uavc niuic uiatt o Ui" j
flcient room, In fact, to fall between any of
the sections of the Eiffel' tower.
				</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1963-12-27/ed-1/?sp=10&q=eiffel+tower</id>
				<rel>0</rel>
				<text></text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1963-12-18/ed-1/?sp=63&q=eiffel+tower</id>
				<rel>0</rel>
				<text></text>
			</result>
			<result>  – doc 13
	
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87065526/1963-11-07/ed-1/?sp=4&q=eiffel+tower</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>PARIS (UPI) Six months ago
Annette Marie Nigen, 33, plunged
from the first platform of the Eiffel
Tower and survived.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1963-08-04/ed-1/?sp=54&q=eiffel+tower&st=text&r=-0.371,-0.087,1.742,1.742,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>rigid as a ram
rod, with the idea that you
are photographing a per
sonal view of the Eiffel
Tower, Taj Mahal, the Na
tion’s Capitol, etc.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86075250/1963-07-12/ed-1/?sp=2&q=eiffel+tower</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>Eiffel oL
Tower ^1
COMPLETED IN 1889,
THIS FAMOUS PARIS WSF
LANDMARK WAS M W
THE TALLEST TOWER Es
BUILT BEFORE sSmSs
THE ADVENT
OF TELEVISION
I'll say it's an
eyeful...and
then some I F CJ
Tower to heights in
this community by
banking with us.</text>
			</result>
		</results>
	</topic>
	<topic>
		<id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-daylight-saving</id>
		<results>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85038411/1918-03-16/ed-1/?sp=15&q=daylight+saving+time</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>)AYLIGHT SAVING
TO GIVE WORKERS
TIME FOR PLAY
'hysicians Believe Move Will
Do Much to Better the
Health of Many
Men who like the great outdoors.'
ho like to leave the offices for a
alk. a little fishing trip nnd a round
f golf—to-day praised the passage 1
t the daylight-saving bill by Con- j
ress.
Physicians here to-day also were j
f the opinion that tho new sched- j
le. to become effective Easter Sun
ay, will do much for thd healUi j
fa great number of workers who'
or the first time will have a chance
3 get out into the parks and fields,
fter a day's work.
Businessmen generally tli rough-
Additional Classified Y

Advertisements on
Opposite Page
1
TOO I, VI I' I'Olt CLASSIFICATION!
REAL ESTATE WANTED
FINE HOTEL FOR RENT
Beautiful, desirable, modern four
tory brick building, Duncannon, Pa.,
•ith "0 rooms, all heated by steam,
or rent- Rent reasonable. Suitable
or apartments. All houses in town
ented. This is good opportunity for j
ight party. Apply T. K. VanDyke,
;o. 21 North Third street. Harrisburg.
a.
GARAGES
ACCESSORIES AND REPAIRS
IF YOUR RADIATOR LEAKS bring
t to us. We'll repair it. We also
epair lamps, fenders, etc.
IARRISBURG AUTO RADIATOR
WORKS,
05 N. THIRD ST. BELL I-XIONE.
BRING your car to us. Experts on
gnitioii and carburetor troubles. 1
Ugliest srade repair work. LEMOYNE I
.UTO SHOP. Lemoyne. Both phones, j
NOW is the time to purchase live j
übber fillers and save the cost of
xtra tires and tubes. Sold by C. E.
inderson, SOl North Eighteenth, 1
ity. Dial 5158. j
WM. PENN GARAGE
04-S Muneeh street. Limousines for
unerals, parties and balls; careful j
irivers; open day and night. Bell
Mt I
YOUR leaky Radiator repaired by j
n expert. Your motor troubles rems-
ied. Rex Garage. 1317 North Third j
ireet.
M<>TOHCYCLES AN D BICYCLES j
REBUILT MOTORCYCLES
1917 Dayton
Twin-cylinder, 9-horse-power, three-
peed with starter, tools, tandem, 111a
hine looks like new. Cost $300.00.
end for our complete list.
Selling Price, $160.00
HEAGY BROS.,
1200 North Third Street.
BICYCLES AND MOTORCYCLES
New and rebuilt bikes at
prices that are not equaled in
the city. Come In and let us
sell you a bike 011 an easy
payment plan. We make terms
10 snit you.
I have personally sold from I
;ou to ::0U bikes each year in
this city for the past several
j ears, which is evident be
yond doubt that my treatment
and prices are tho best.
Guaranteed repairing at
reasonable prices, by men
who know how to do work
right.
This is the season of the
year to have your bike putin
good shape for the summer
season. Let us give you an
estimate on the .iob.
Repairing ol all kinds, re
nickuling. rc-cnamellng, weld
ing, straightening; frames or
anything pertaining to a bike
<>r motorcycle. We aim to give
the best service in the cits.
Write, phone or call.
Bell 355.1 Dial 3590
C. A. SPRENKLE
Cycle and Auto Supply Co.
107 Market St.
BICYCLES. BICYCLES,
s'ew and rebuilt bicycles at very at
tractive prices; guarauteed repair
ing; come here and get a square deal.
H. F. EST EHE ROOK,
912 N. Third Street.
Dial 4990.
BICYCLES TO HIRE
DAY OR WEEK.
DAYTON CYCLE CO..
912 N. 3rd ST. DIAL 4990.
BICYCLE REPAIRING
BY AN ENPERT.
ALL WORK GUARANTEED
DORY SIIANER
WITH
ANDREW REDMOND
BICYCLE
SUPPLIES AND REPAIRING.
SATISFACTION CU A R ANTEED.
CYCLE ft AUTO SUPPLY CO.,
Cleaners anil D;en
SAVE your clothes. Get them clean
ed, pressed, dyed or repaired at Good
man's. 1306% North Sixth St. We do It
right. Phones. Call and deliver.
I'l BI.IC SALE"T
PUBLIC SALE
The undersigned will offer at Public
?ale, on the premises, one-half mile
101 th of Progress.- on Wednesday,
fctaroh 20, commencing at 1 o'clock
M.. Bight Horses, 12 young grade
lolstoin Cows, 7 Holstein Heifers and
I Holstein Bull, 22 head of Hogs, 2
Jorries, 2 Top Buggies, 7 Sets of
Jght Harness, 1 No. 2 Cooley
.fiamer, 1 INewtown Coal-burning
"plony Brooder, and other articles
lot mentioned.
B. FRANK OBER.
r
AUCTION SALE
At -the residence of the late
JOHN C. JENNINGS.
1426 North Second Street,
MONDAY, MARCH 18. 1918.
At 1:30 P. M.
XsiaSating of solid walnut bedroom
mite, ball and stair carpet. 3 rugs,
itteliati table, refrigerator, large lot
>f ".r'-ple-jilated silverware, three
tnatter niHi double beds, framed pie
ures. plush davenport, dishes and
:Ool:ing utensils, and other articles
00 numerous to mention. Terms:
E. P. JENNINGS. Administrator.
MAXWELL H. HITE, Auctioneer.
LEGAL NOTICES
ADMINISTRATOR'S NOTICE
restate of Harry P. Eisenhart. late of
Harrisburg, Pa., deceased.
LETTERS OF ADMINISTRATION
>n .-aiil estate have been granted to
he undersigned, residiiKT in said
•Ity. All persons having claims or
lemands against said estate will make
iebt.ed to said decedent will make
payment, without delay, to
ANNA V. EISENHART,
1409 N. Second St.
SATURDAY EVENING, HARRISBURG iKfeAl TELEGRAPH MARCH 16, 1918.
out the city this afternoon declared
that the changing of hours would
be accomplished without interrupt
ing or hurting trade. It was said
that tho change would mean little
or nothing to the larger mills ahd
munitions plants, where three shifts
of men now ure engaged in working
throughout the twenty-four hours, j
No difficulty will be experienced in
trolley car schedules, it was said at
the offices of the Harrisburg and
'cross-river traction companies and
the turning of the watch will do
the trick. i
Theaters, railroads and every bus-
iness house in the city will operate
according to the now schedule, and,
therefore, it was pointed out, there
can be 110 confusion after a man
has once reset his watch.
Summed up, Mr, Littlefleld says:
"The bill provides tor an hour
advance in standard time at 2
o'clock a. in. on the last Sunday
in .March of each yefcr and at
a. m. the lust Sunday in October
uie standard time shall be retarded
one hour. Eleven countries have
adopted the summer daylight sav-
ing plan. The first was Germany,
then Great Britain, France, Austria-
Hungary, Italy, Sweden, Denmark,
Norway, Holland, Portugal and Au-/
stralla. London, England, saved
200,000 tons of coal during a sum
mer. In England in five and one
half months $12,000,000 in coal '.vere
saved, and In France $10,000,000. It
is estimated that in the United States
$10,000,000 can be saved in light
bills. The hour of daylight con
served by the proposed law can be
used by industrial workers throug
out America for gardening and agri
cultural work. This will be a most
important gain. We are sure of a
great shortage in farm labor this
summer and something must be done
to offset the probable loss in pro
duction of farm products. The hour
saved for daylight every day in April.
				</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045433/1918-03-16/ed-1/?sp=1&q=act+change+changes+Clock+daylight+daylight-saving+HOURS+law+Saving+standard+time</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>DAYLIGHT SAVING TIMl
3HOURS
VASTED
lYLJGHT
r" I'nY
8HOUR WORKDAY
FREE
LIGHT
HOURS

ItlGHI
These charts show vividly how the daylight saving plan will give j
everybody more "free hour#" of daylight. You've heard this: "Well,!
there are just so many hours of daylight in a day and you can't change j
'em." But wait?the daylight hours before your work-day itarts are
so-called "wasted hours"?you ?leep them away or spend them getting
ready to go to work. The daylight saving plan merely "shifts" an
hour of daylight to the "free hours" after work, when you can use it.
The tables is based on the average June day and the workday from
8 to 5 includes an hour for lunch.
Moving the Clock.
The clock will be set forward one
hour at 2 a. m., March SI, according
to the House bill. At the same hour
on October 27, the clock will be set
back.
The present standard time rones
will remain in effect.
Both changes will take place on
Sunday mornings so that the least
possible wrench may be given to
the industrial fabric of the nation.
But even at that on the railroads
alone there will be some 1.000 pas
senger trains and 5.000 trains run
ning on the tracks when the change
comes, and 1,698.SIS railroad clocks
and watches must be set forward
to keep traffic moving and prevent j together. At present In summer
accidents. In 1883. however, a sim- j London closes as New York opens,
ilar change from local to standard i More time for golf, amateur base
time went into effect on 100,000 ball and tennis.
miles of railroad without a single
mishap.
Benefits of Plan.
The following benefits will be
reaped by the daylight-saving plan:
Saving of one to one and a half
million tons of coal per year, ac
cording to Fuel Administration es
timates.
Increased food production by sub
urban gardeners.
Less traffic accidents.
Improvement in health of all the
people. More fresh air. Women
workers will return from work in
daylight.
Speeding up of freight transpor
tation by giving extra hour at docks
and terminals.
New York and London Stock Ex
changes will be open for one ho'
:i;
Nation Moves Clocks Up
One Hour Easter Sunday
Daylight Saving Bill Passes House by Big Ma
jority as War Measure?Some Opposition
from Farming Communities.
Clocks all over the oountry will
be set ahead one hour, beginning
March 31, under the so-called day
light-saving bill, pessed yesterday by
the House, 252 to 40.
Senator Calder, author of the
ure In the upp?r braftch iftf Congress,
said the House amendments would
be agreed to, so that a conference
would not be necessary.
Provisions of Bill.
The bill provides that at 2 o'clock
p. m. on the last Sunday In March
each year, clocks all over the country
which affect any operations of the
Federal government, or railroads,
i shall be set ahead one hour. At 2
j o'clock p. m., the last Sunday in Oc
j tober of each year, they are to be
i retarded one hour.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030431/1918-03-24/ed-1/?sp=58&q=daylight+saving+time</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>Daylight Saving Is Simplicity Itself
How Ben Franklin s Idea Conceived in 1784, Just Made Into Law Here, Will Affect
Folks After Easter and Save Millions to the Nation
10
By WM. ARCHIBALD FERGUSON,
Secretary of the National Daylight Sar
ins Association.
ON Ihc coming Apwl 1 more people
in the United Slates will probably
be April fool vietims than on any previ
ous or future April 1, for Congress lias
decreed that at 2 o'clock on the morning
of March 31 the hands of the clock shall
be turned forward one hour; in other
words, the United States will then begin
to live under the davlight saving plan,
and doubtless thousands will forget to
make the change.
Every individual who is wise Jind hates
to be fooled will before retiring on the
evening prior to Kaster Sunday, March
31, see to it that not onh his watch but
every clock in the bou.se is turned for
ward one hour. Otherwise on Sunday he
will find the Easter services half over be
fore he arrives at the church, and on
Monday morning, April 1, VMS, rising
an hour late, if he is a commuter he will
miss his morning train by an hour and
be greeted at the factory or office with
such remarks as "April fool!" "You day
light blacker! You forgot to turn your
watch ahead, eh 7'' and all day long he
will be the butt of many jokes.
May Wait Lone for Dinner.
If lie starts for home at the tame hour
as usual and has not during the day tele
phoned his wife to turn the clock ahead
be will have a long wail tor dinner. One
thing Is certain, hotvivcr. that before he
retires that night crry member of his
household will know that the daylight pav
ing plan is in effect and that the people
of the United States are living an hour
ahead of sun time.
The daylight sating idea U almost as
Id as the United States it-elf and our
country can rightly claim the credit for
all the many advantages which will act-rue
from it, not only in this country bat also
in those countries which anticipated the
United Slates in its adoption, for it was
Benjamin Pranklm who Iirst conceited
the idea.
On an early morning walk along the
Etreels of Imdou in 17.S4 the thought Iirst
came to him, and in passing if on to the
world at large he said:
''In a walk through the Strand and Tit et
ttrect one morning at 7 o'clock I ob.-Ttcd
then; was not one shop open, although
it had been davlight ami the sun up
above three hours, the inhabitants of
lxndon choo.-iug voluntarily to live by
candle light and sleei by sun-bine; and
yet often complaining :t little absurdly of
the dnty on candles and the high price
of tallow.''
Soon thereafter in the Jtwrnal Je
Faris he publL-hcd an article, later ap
pearing among his es-ays under the title
4An Economical Project," which further
elaborated the advantages of daylight sav
ing; namely, of "Turning the clock for
ward an hour" so that everybody would
live one hour longer by davlight and one
hour less by artificial light.
Beaten Repeatedly in Britain.
Tor many years in England in the
last century Sir William Willctt annually
introduced his davlight sating bill in Par
liament and annually the bill wa- de
feated amid laughter and ridicule.
In 1915 Germany tirst adopted the plan
to speed np the war production and io
benefit by the tremendous saving in fuel
consumption. France and England and
nil other European countries except Rus
sia soon alter followed her example.
Since its adoption in Europe, the.
United State.-, Canada and Mexico have
been out of harmony, so far as time was
concerned, with European countries, to
their loss not only in business, for the
stock exchanges of Ixindon and Paris un
der the new plan were closed before the
exchanges of New York and I tost on were
open, but also as regards the tremendous
savings pos-ible in light bills, which, it
is estimated, annually will run from V0,
000,000 to $50,000,000 in the United
Sfates alone.
The plan has been ardently advocated
in this country since May, Wlfi, by the
Merchants Association of this city, cham
bers of commerce of Boston, Rochester,
Philadelphia, Chicago and Pittsburg, the
United States Chamber of Commerce,
Washington, D. C, and the National Day
light Saving Association, of which Marcus
M. Marks, former Borough President of
Manhattan, is the president. Mr. Marks
has often been called the '"'father of day
light saving in this country."
To illustrate the effect of the. plan, let
us follow Jack Hurryup, a New York
commuter, through his first business day
under the new regime.
Mr. Hurryup is a habitual reader of
The Scn, and accordingly he knows he
should on the evening of March 30 turn
his watch and clocks ahrad one hour be
fore he retires at 9 o'clock. But on the
night of Easter Sunday he goes through
the house from the kitchen to the
roof and advances each clock one hour
and is surprised when he arritis iu his
bed chamber and looks at his watch to
lind that he is retiring at 10:1.1 instead
of i:15 his lirst shock from daylight
saving.
The alarm dock rings louder than
usual the next morning and he. jumps out
that several of his friends to whom he
telephones have not yet arrived at the
office, but are expected auy minntt.
At 1 o'clock, his usual hour, he hurries
to the restaurant for luncheon and finds
a slim crowd. Upon returning to the of
fice all is running smoothly and at quar
ter of 5 he closes his desk to catch the
5:15. As he passes through the gate at
the Grand Central he sees the same fa
miliar crowd starting on their nightly
journey home.
Ed, Kill and Dick are on hand for the
nightly game of poker, .lack and his
friend Ed were the losers in the game,
for they spent most of their time joking
Bill and Dick for being April fools aud
having missed the train in the morning.
Alighting from the commuters' special
in the country, he is happily pleased to
note that it has not vet begun to grow
BENJAMIN FRANKLIN
jr FROM THE ENGRAVING OF THE DUPLESSIS' PORTRAIT OF 1778
Noted American philosopher is the father of daylight saving.
of bed at C:.'J0, leans out of the window
and noles that the sun is ju-t ri-ing, and
then realizes that he is really getting up
one hour earlier by the sun, although the
alarm went off at the usual hour.
He rushes through his bath and his
breakfast and runs for the train. When
he arrives at the station he is surprised to
find many of his pals missing. The train
pulls in and he runs to his customary scat
in the smoker: the table and the cards
are there, but only one plajcr besides
himself. He greets Ed .(ones, who
boarded the train at the station, above
with:
"Good April fool joke on Bill and
Dick! Guess they forgot to turn their
watches ahead last night. We'll have
some sport with them to-morrow."
Mr. Hurryup piles into the subway
aud is astonished to lind a seat at the
Grand Central, his second shock from
the daylight saving. "Guess a lot of peo
ple are fooled by this daylight saving
this morning," he mutters to himself.
He arrives at the office, looks at the
clock to see whether he has consumed the
usual time on his journey down town and
is surprised to find that he is arriving
at 8:1.1, the exact time at which he took
the tram at his station. Shock No. 3.
No oflice boy in sight. He rings for his
stenographer and she greets him with a
hearty "Good morning He tells her
to get the porter immediately and turn
that oflice clock ahead one hour.
He finds no mail on his desk and con
cludes that the letter carrier is also one of
the daylight saving April fo;Is.
The morning runs on as usual except
dark and that the sun is still shining
brightly at 0 o'clock. "We fooled ton to
day. Old Sol, and will keep fooling you
until November 1," he says to himself.
Arriving at the house he goes to the
cellar, and finding that he need not turn
on the lights he gels out the lawn mower
and bis garden tools.
"This daylight sating is all right," he
calls up fo Mary; ''don't hurry to get on
the dinner. I am going to mow the lawn
and wotk in the garden until sundown."
After an hour's work about the grounds
.lack comes in to dinner and he anil Mary
agree that daylight saving is the greatest
boon ever conferred upon New York com
muters. The chief benefits of the plan, as
proved by the experience of England,
France and other European countries
where it has been in force, may be gen
erally summarized under three heads:
Eirst General health of all people
benefited by reason of an added hour of
daylight in the late afternoon, which has
been and will be u-ed for outdoor recre
ation and exercise.
Second Increased production of food
stuffs through the stimulating cultivation
of home gardening.
Third Money saved in lighting bills:
each householder will burn artificial light
one hour less each day, provided, of
course, he continues his usual habits of
retiring at night.
The report of the summertime commit
tee appointed by the British Parliament
in September, 1!1G, to inquire into the
social and economic results of the sum
mertime act shows that the extra hour of
dat light was generally ucd for the pur-po-e
of outdoor recreation and pursuit's,
and, in particular, for the cultivation of
home gardening.
The athletic dubs reported that the
cricketers, bowlers, golfers and tennii
players took full advantage of the extra
hour of light, and swimming pools and
playgrounds were utilized to full capac
ity. Iu view of the national agitation last
year, which is being renewed now, for
the cultivation of home gardens to in
crease the production of food the inaugu
ration of the daylight saving plan iu this
country will undoubtedly very greatly
stimulate home gardening, particularly in
the neighborhood of the great cities. In
New York city alone there are 1,000.000
daily commuters. Should only one-half
of them use the extra hour of daylight
which the plan will give in cultivating
home gardens there will bo 3,000,000 extra
hours utilized weekly in gardening and
during the seven summer months in which
the plan is in operation 2,000,000 days of
extra work and time will be spent by
these 500,000 commuters in the cultiva
tion of gardens.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88064305/1918-03-28/ed-1/?sp=1&q=daylight+saving+time</id>
				<rel>0</rel>
				<text></text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1918-03-30/ed-1/?sp=2&q=daylight+saving</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>Aat Hour Of Daylight Beginning Tomorrow Morning
te&mmMmauim amhmm kiimmmmmssmm y-irmmsmm
…
If you do so understand the daylight-saving-
law, and there are many
who are puzzled, do .not worry. Just
before going- to bed tonight advance
your clock one hour that Is. 
…
Tbere is no occasion for the slightest confusion in
the matter of daylight saving, which begin tomorrow.
All you have to do is when you go to bed tonight, set
your clock oxK hour ahead. Get up at the regular time,
BY THE CLOCK, and proceed as usuaL The simplest
statement of the whole thing is set the clock arc hour
ahead and follow the clock.
HaYe7f aDatefor
2:30 Ton new Mora?
BetYouDon'tKeepIt
Til meet you at 2:30 o'clock,
in the morning,' said one man
to another in front of Tho Tlmea
today.-"
Tes No you won't either."
"Why, you -poor fish. You can
certainly be there at 2:S0.
"Wrong-. Archie. Follow to
closely. There will be no 2 JO in
the morning. When the daylight
savings law goes into effect at
2 o'clock the hands on the clock:
will "be moved around one hour to
3 o'clock. So there will be no
ha'.." past two." l
-Welt I'll be
day nights will ,jct 'a short night, as
the' clock will Jnmp' from 2 to 3
o'clock.
Sleep Henr Less.
If you do not have to work to
night you will get an hour's less
sleep than usual, unless you go to
bed an hour earlier than usual to
make up for' the hour the clocks will
skip. If you turn up the clock an
ALLEYLAWMAY
BESTOW)
hour before) g-otag- to bed and then go
to bed accordingly, you wlti get the
usual night's sleep. For instance. If
the usual bedtime is 11 o'clock, turn -the
clock up one hour at 10 from 10
to 11 and go. to bed. The only'
necessary change for you then under,
the daylight saving- law has been I
made, and you have BO'further wor-l
ries.</text>
			</result>
			<result> – doc 6
	
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87057262/1918-03-30/ed-1/?sp=7&q=daylight+saving</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>f You Play Golf Just Think of the
Extra Daylight You'll Have to
Chase Over the
Green.
JUST DO THIS AND BE CONTENT.
8et all clocks and timepieces ahead
One hour Just before retiring Saturday
night.
Those who are awake at 2 a. m.,
Sunday, may wait until that hour to
set their timepieces ahead one hour.
Ahead—-forward—one hour. Under
stand this and do it, and having done
it, be content, nor worry any more
about it.
This simple Instruction, obeyed so
thoroughly that every timepiece in
the oountry la thus changed one hour
ahead, will carry out the law and pre
vent any confusion whatever. Every
phase of life will move ahead with the
cloaks—trains, street cars, business,
religious services—everything. The 9
o'clock trains Sunday morning will
leave at 9 o'clock by the clock. The 7
o'clock atreet cars will run at 7 o'clock
by the clock—everything will be Juet I
as it Is now, by the clock. And the riotic
clock will be the only thing to rely on
as
It Is now. Just what!his
the clock says, after It has been turned
ahead one hour, that will be the time,
and the time for everything, Just as It
is now. There will be no change in
anything except the clocks and
watches, and no one need pay any at
tention to the fact that they have been
moved one hour ahead.
Complete plans for the daylight sav
ing system, which' goes into effect to
morrow have been announced by fed
eral officials and the nation's workers
are ready to push the hands of the
•clock one hour ahead to assist Uncle
Sam In hig fight for liberty.
Every city in the country, every
town and village, everything is in
readiness for the new system, a sys
tem that will save the nation thou
sands of tons of coal daily as well as
assisting the working man, the shop
girl and the laboring clasa as well as
the busy office man.
What this plan means to the nation
can be described in a few words. In
the first place It means the conserva
tion of the fuel supply. Secondly,-it
gives the average man more time to
devote to gardening, which In turn
means a "bigger supply of food for the
nation and, thirdly, it means a more
healthy nation.
The work of the masses will be done
In daylight, where, heretofore, it was
done In the dark a certain number of
hours a day.
Favored by All.
Since the plan was first spoken of
it has attracted the attention of some
of the biggest men in the country.
Efficiency experts have studied the
plans and in very instance have re
turned a favorable report on their
study.
The action has been favored by
President Wilson for the past several
months. Garfield and Hoover have
been ardent supporters of the plan.
There has never been an argument
against the system and every learned
man in the country is of the J.rsllef that
the plan will greatly aid the nation's
savings.
The daylight saving plan will give
the following daily advantages:
One hour or more for outdoor rec
reation. Recreation is a national as
set, an immense force for health and
moral well-being.
Working mothers and fathers obtain
an extra hour for outdoor play with
their children, both summer and win
ter.
One hour less for bad lights in tene
ments.
Lessened eyestrain for workers and
school children due to the use of artifi
cial light.
Smaller risk of accident in indus
trial establishments, because there
jwill he a light hour instead of a dark
one at the end of the working day at
,tlie time of greatest fati-gue and most
{frequent accidents.
Lessened risk of accidents due to
I transportation and traffic conditions,
because the afternoon rush will fall in
iduylight Instead of darkness,
Working girls will be on the way
home in the daylight instead of in the
!dark in winter.
Our last hour of sleep will be sound
ier and more 'beneficial than it is un
der present conditions, because there
will be less light.
General efficiency will, of course, be
•increased by any improvement in the
(health morals and social welfare of
tiie workers and others.
Morning Coolness.
I In summer a cool hour In the morn
jing is substituted for a hot one In
I the afternoon.
I In winter a light hour at the end of
the day is substituted for a dark one.
This is especially valuable com^g as
it does at the time of greatest fatigue,
and is peculiarly valuable in some in
dustries where aocurate eyesight is
essential.
Efficiency is lowest in the later aft
ernoon, the time when- accidents are
roost frequent.
There will be the greatest of all sav
ings—that of hnman materials, as
pointed out above.
Immediate saving in form of reduc
tion of expense for light and heat.
Ultimate saving in the conservation
QPHE DAILY GATE CITY^
of coal and other sources of light and
heat
Possilble reduction in the cost of liv^
ing of those who like to work in their
gardens, utilizing the extra outdoor
hour for this purpose.
A memorandum containing the fol
lowing important reasons tor the uni
versal adoption of the daylight saving
plan, looking at the matter from the
standpoint of war needs, was sent to
the house committee in February:
The training of the national forces
will be expedited, and the practice of
home guards and similar organiza
tions, the members of which have oth
er regular occupations, will be great
ly facilitated.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030193/1918-03-30/ed-1/?sp=3&q=daylight+saving</id>
				<rel>0</rel>
				<text></text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1918-03-31/ed-1/?sp=8&q=daylight+saving&st=text&r=-0.292,-0.172,1.304,1.304,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>Daylight saving as war measure
compulsory. It is ilmated .that
the measure will rts-ult In a cut of
M j nat,on., blI1
tor artificial Sight
The change tn the Government de-1
Ipartments, the, a to res, business houses
office's-' of. -Washington will b
affected practically without notice.
Clock were turned up at the close of
business last night, or during the
morning today. The hands on the big
postoffice clock were turned up at
p. ra. this morj-itnsr. the official hour
for the change.
The Senate, however, took time by
thhe forelock yesterday and moved
the Senate clock up at 2 o'clock 'in
tbo afternoon. Senator Caltler of
I Sew York, who sponsored the day-
Jthe clock up there twelve l.mirs be-,
!'u1
fore schedule. Ills performance was I

i ji lAict "iiaiii? niiu iiianuiaL'iiii
.era' Association put the clock ahead
one hour at the clo.r- of business yes-

terday. It was tunfed up by Secre
tary C. J. Colurabuy. It was an
nounced that there would b" no
change ln store or other business
hours in Washington.
MARINES AT QUANTICO
WILL PRESENT-SHOW
,..c w.u.. raiiro-ls for proposal on (lie ron-
irrespective of the clock or time .miction of niO.tMMi freight cars. Tin
One of the, most. pretentious .-a.nip record. car, will be of a standaid dcj-lk-n. de-
theatrical productions ever attemp'
ed will be given by the men of the
heavy artillery farces at Ihe Marine
Corp Theater at Quantico next
Thursday evening under the title of
"The Marine Itevue
More than -IX) marines will tal.e
part In the show, which is a musics I
comedy-minstrel show combined. It
Is to be the exclusive production of
the enlisted men of the marine corps.
Klaborate stage effects of the show
are the work of Kirst Sergt. H. H.
Hudde. formerly manager" and dlrec-'
tor of a theater in Chicago. T.he
I mus'c In prepared and directed by
Private IV. W. Multrr. former soloist
for the.PhJladelrrhia Oj-chestra.
PALMER TAKES OVER
BREWERY SUPPLY CO.
A. Mitchell Pslmer. alien nronertv
custodian, bus taken oer the K. and
li KeurconJ,Cotnpany. .of Nev .Qr-
e.n:
r,,e ev.ny-rroiks brerr siir.-
pIlcK and l.os r.100,000 capital stock,
r 'ai-.e iX oT" which Ts' enemy'
icrt, f j.nurltr Pyk, vice president
ui -th.-JUiltny. intral -National
nk or Xew Orleans, has bee,,
T to mt Be director
Text of Daylight Saving Law
An act to save daylight and to provide, standard time for the United
Be it enacted by the Senate and
United' States of America m. Congress -ossemDiea, mat, ior ine.pur-.
pose of establishing the, standard time of the United States, the ter
ritory of continental Umted States shall be divided .into five zones in
the manner hereinafter provided. The standard time of the. first zone
shall be based on the mean 'astronomical time of the second, .zone, on
the.ninetieth degree; that of the third zone, on the one hundred and
fifthdegree; that, of thefourth zone on .the one hundred and twentieth
degree, ard that of the fifth zone, which shall include only Alaska, on
the" one hundred and fiftieth' degree. That the limits of "each zone shall
K AofmaA hv an nrtloi- nf thp Interstate Commerce Commission, having..
regard for the convenience f commerce and the existing. jucc.tion J
points and division point 'of common .carriers engaged in commerce-J
between the several States' and. with foreign nations, ana sucn oruer
'may be modified, from time to time.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87057262/1918-04-01/ed-1/?sp=5&q=daylight+saving&st=text&r=0.21,0.022,0.465,0.465,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>Keoktik observed the daylight sav
ing law Sunday morning by turning
the clocks ahead one hour. And every
The earth Is approximately 24,000
miles around. It makes a full turn in
twenty-four hours, or travels at the.
rate of say one thousand miles per
hour. We poor mortals, clinging to
the earth as best we can are being
whirled around at this excessive rate
of speed. We are going some. Yet
Sunday morning at 2 o'clock, when the
clocks were changed, we made an ex
tra jump of a thousand miles in our
mad race. Did you notice the change?
The miser has $200,000 out at inter
est at six per cent. His income from
this is $1.37 every hour of the day.
Sunday morning he made an extra
$1.37 when the clocks were changed.
But when the clock is changed iback in
October, he will lose an equal amount.
The sick man was to be given a pill
every half hour. The nurse had been
instructed to be very careful in fol
lowing out the instructions. Some
body changed the clock and she got all
muddled up as to whether to give the
dying, man two extra pills. It was a
case of life and death. The nurse
fainted and the poor sick man got no
pills all night long. When the nurse
regained consciousness, her patient
had recovered and was out working in
his war garden.
The early worm had become tired
of dodging the early bird every morn
ing, so the worm made his trips over
the top an hour earlier each day. But
the bird observed the new daylight
savings law and met the worm half
way as usual.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1927-09-23/ed-1/?sp=29&q=daylight+savings</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>The Daylight Savings Ghost
Again Rears Its Head
The ghost of daylight savings once more bobs up.
Although Congress refused to enact a daylight-savings law
for the Distrcit just after the war, another attempt may be
made to obtain congressional consideration for it.
Voluntarily in force here during the war, daylight savings
Created such confusion that the proposition to make it
permanent by law was bitterly fought. Congress, usually de
lighted to fasten theories upon the District, balked in the face
of the strong opposition, especially from farmers and farm
organizations.
Congress will probably be of the lame, mind this winter if
a bill for District daylight savings is submitted.
As a recreation measure, daylight savings is strongly favored,
but for domestic and business purposes it doesn't stand so
well. Despite laws in a number of States and cities, passed
when the daylight savings fad was at its heighth, the scheme
has made little or no recent progress. The large Eastern
railroads continue to adhere to standard time throughout the
year.
Daylight savings imposes its worst hardships upon city
housewives and farm and suburban households. Housewives
enjoy none of its benefits. Their hours of work, oh the con
trary, are lengthened.
In this city, for example, the mother of a family going to
work at different hours of the day would be serving breakfast
at varying hours of the morning to suit the employment hours
of her husband and children. The boarding housekeeper
Would be in the same fix.
The servant problem is another factor that leads to the
upsetting of domestic routine and family habits.
It was impossible during our trial of daylight savings to
reconcile working hours in this city. In the Government de
partments there were different hours of going to work and
leaving work. This added to the burdens of housekeepers.
Mothers, with children in schools* were compelled to arouse
their children an hour earlier than customary, but found it
almost impossible to get them to bed at night an hour earlier.
In the opinion of many physicians, mothers and children did
not get the sleep they were accustomed to and should have.
The advantages of daylight savings, as viewed by its work
ings here, were far less than the disadvantages, which in
cluded Upset domestic conditions and considerable chaos.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045499/1949-04-23/ed-1/?sp=1&q=daylight+savings</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>Daylight Saving Time
at 2 A.M. Sunday
NEW YORK, April 23. UP)—About
50,000.000 Americans will be cheat
ed out of an hour's sleep to
night with the advent of daylight
savings time.
Most of the big cities turn their
clocks ahead cns hoar at 2 a.m. on
feur.day.
Residents will have to wait until
September 25 to get back their
“lost hour.” At that time clocks
go back an hour.
The object of daylight savings
time is to allow daytime workers
to enjoy an added hour of day
light after the quitting whistle.
For that reason it is most popu
lar in heavily-settled areas.
Large cities going on “fast time"
include Portland, Me., Boston, Prov
idence, New York, Newark, Phila
delphia, Pittsburgh, Baltimore.
Washington, Cleveland, Chicago, In
dianapolis, St. Louis and Portland,
Oregon.
Seattle waits until June to change
i its clocks.
j* Some cities that had daylight
savings time a year ago have
f abandoned it this year. They in
clude Los Angeles, San Francisco,
Detroit, Chattanooga and Nash
ville.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84020662/1949-04-25/ed-1/?sp=4&q=daylight+savings&r=-0.059%2C0.327%2C1.423%2C0.757%2C0&st=text</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>Americans got cheated out of
an hour’s sleep Saturday night
with the advent of daylight sav
ings time. Most of the big cities
turned their clocks ahead one
hour at 2 a.m., Sunday.
Residents will have to wait un
til September 25 to get back their
“lost hour.” At that time, clocks
will go back an hour.
The object of daylight savings
time is to allow daytime workers
to enjoy an added hour of daylight
alter the quitting whistle. For that
reason ill is most popular in heav
ily-settled areas.
Large cities going on “fasttime”
include Portland, Me., Boston,
Providence, New York, Newark.
Philadelphia, Pittsburgh, Balti
more. Washington, Cleveland, Chi
cago, Indianapolis, St. Louis, and
Portland, Ore.
Seattle waits until June to
change its clocks.
Some cities that had daylight
savings time a year ago have
j abandoned it this year. They in
clude Los Angeles, San Francisco,
Detroit, Chattanooga and Nash
ville.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88064305/1919-08-28/ed-1/?sp=1&q=daylight+savings&st=text&r=-0.316,0.111,0.981,0.981,0</id>
				<rel>0</rel>
				<text></text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84022396/1931-04-16/ed-1/?sp=13&q=daylight+savings&st=text&r=-0.256,-0.032,1.511,1.511,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>PREDICTS DAYLIGHT
SAVING WON'T LAST
Chief of Weather Bureau Say* Ad
vancad Time i* a Nui*ance
The practice of observing daylight
saving schedules by business organ
izations in at least 33 cities in Con
necticut, including New Haven,
Bridgeport, Stamford, Hartford and
Waterbury, as well as throughout the
entire country, should be abandon
ed for the reason that daylight sav
ing schedules are a "nuisance, ac
cording to Dr. C. F. Marvin, Chief
of the Weather Bureau.
A survey revealed that in spite of
a law in Connecticut making it an
offense to show other than standard
time on clocks or timepieces publicly
displayed, daylight time is observed
by business organizations in at least
33 cities in the state. This law, it
was pointed out, was an attempt to
prohibit the observance of daylight
savings.
Dr. Marvin predicted that observ
ance of daylight savings wiil event
ually be abandoned because the plan
inconveniences more people than it
benefits and because it upsets the
chronology of scientific studies. In
the United States, he declared, the
repeated changes in clock time create
difficulties in maintaining railroad
schedules, hamper farmers in their
marketing activities and even dis
comforts the city employe who is sup
posed to benefit most from the plan.
The survey showed that daylight
time was observed during 1930
throughout the entire states of Mas
sachusetts and Rhode Island. Maine
has a state law similar to that of
Connecticut, prohibiting observance
of other than Eastern Stamlaid
Time. Two cities in New Hampshire
and one in Vermont observe day
light savings.</text>
			</result>
		</results>
	</topic>
</topics>
